Dominic J. Badolato Papers 2003.0137
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Inventory, undated, 1918-2003
  - Bowling (1955-65), State of Connecticut Labor Department (1957-1965), New Britain Democratic Party (1960s), State of Connecticut Personnel Department (1960-1967), Workmen's Compensation (1961-1963), New Britain Charter Revision Commission (1962), Connecticut Municipal Employee Retirement Fund (1962), Unemployment Compensation (1962-1964), Connecticut State Board of Mediation and Arbitration (1965), New Britain and AFSCME Agreement (1965-1967), Connecticut State Labor Relations Board (1966-1968), State of Connecticut Democratic Party (1966-1968), Greater Hartford Area Salary Survey (1967), and Municipal Employee Relations Act (1968), 1955-1968 (Box 28)
  - AFSCME 14th Biennial Convention Amendments (1964), AFSCME 14th International Credential Committee Report (1964), AFSCME 14th Biennial Convention Resolutions (1964), Constitution Revision Commission Report (1966), AFSCME Publication (1968), Connecticut State Legislative booklets (1970s), AFSCME (1970-1985), Journals of the House and Senate (1972-1980), Connecticut Municipal Employees' Retirement Fund (1974), newspaper clippings (1974), AFSCME 21st International Convention Call Records (1975), AFSCME Convention Amendments (1976), AFSCME Structural Committee Report (1976), The Wave AFSCME Convention Bulletins (1976), AFSCME 22nd International Convention Amendments (1976), AFSCME International Executive Board (1977), Labor Institute of Public Affairs (1984), AFSCME International Executive Board (1985), and "Akron City Employees Local 1360" Disaffiliation Report (1985), 1964-1985 (Box 29)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1973-1977) (Box 30)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1974-1977) (Box 31)
  - Badolato's New Britain Trust Company mail (1964), Badolato's Legislative Council binder (1967-1969), Badolato's House of Representatives Calendar (1976), Badolato's General Assembly bills (1976), Badolato's Journals of the House (1976), Badolato's House of Representatives Files (1976), Badolato's Labor Center Building Dedication booklet (1987), 5th Annual Worker's Memorial Day booklet (1993), AFSCME International Executive Board Judicial Panel Report (1996), Connecticut Council 4 News Bulletin regarding Badolato's retirement (1997), and a Tribute to Dom Badolato booklet (1998), 1964-1998 (Box 32)
  - Badolato's Office of Legislative Research Bill Analysis (1976), and AFSCME International Executive Board (1996), 1976-1996 (Box 33)
  - New Britain Charter Revision Commission (1977), New Britain Charter Revision Commission Proposals (1977), Interview Material for Connecticut State Labor Council COPE Director (1979), Connecticut Council 4 (1980s), New Britain Charter Revision Commission (1989), AFSCME (1992-1996), Badolato's mail (1993), AFSCME International Executive Board (1997), and Connecticut Council 4 Executive Board (1997), 1977-1998 (Box 34)
  - Committee on Public Information (1918), AFSCME (1950s-1990s), Connecticut Council 4 (1975-1981), newspaper clippings (1976), Connecticut State Labor Council Legislative Program (1976), Occupational Health and Safety of Municipal Workers manual (1977), City of New Britain Connecticut Charter (1980), New Britain Charter Revision Commission (1980-1989), State of Connecticut Municipal Employee Union (1983), Connecticut Council 4 memorandum to Badolato (1990), AFSCME International Constitution handbook (1996), AFSCME and United Staff Union Agreement (1996-1999), Ferrucci et al v. Badolato et al (1997-1998), and AFSCME 33rd International Convention Amendments (1998), 1918-1999 (Box 35)
  - Judicial Panel Chairmen's Report (1977), AFSCME Pension Fund Trustees Manual (1990s), AFSCME Fighting for the Future (1990s), AFSCME (1998), AFSCME Fighting for the Future Officers Report (1998), AFSCME Fighting for the Future Judicial Panel handbooks (1998), AFSCME 33rd International Convention (1998), Preliminary Report of the Task Force for AFSCME's Future (1998), AFSCME Task Force for the Future Financial Presentation (1998), AFSCME (1998-1999), AFSCME 33rd International Executive Board (1998), and International Executive Board Judicial Panel Report (1998), 1977-1999 (Box 36)
  - Connecticut Council 4 (1990s), AFSCME International Constitution booklets (1996), AFSCME Voters Guide pamphlet (1997), Connecticut Conference of Municipalities salary survey (1997), AFSCME (1997), Connecticut State AFL-CIO Financial Statements (1997-1998), Miller et al v. Badolato (1997-1998), AFSCME Fighting for the Future Judicial Panel booklet (1998), AFSCME Fighting for the Future Officers Report (1998), "Independent" Union news flyer (1998), AFSCME promotional publications (1998), AFSCME 33rd International Convention Call and Credentials (1998), AFSCME Patient Protections in Managed Care booklet (1998), Connecticut Council 4 (1998), and AFSCME Public Employee magazine (1999), 1990s-1999 (Box 37)
  - AFSCME promotional material packet (1967), AFSCME 17th International Convention Proceedings (1968), AFSCME 18th International Convention Proceedings (1970), AFSCME 19th International Convention Proceedings (1972), Department of Labor booklets (1986-1987), Department of Labor (1986-1987), AFSCME Pre-Election Conference (1986-1990), AFSCME 28th International Convention Credentials Committee Report (1988), AFL-CIO Public Employee Department Conference (1988), AFSCME (1988-89), New Britain Police Committee (1989), and Department of Labor (1989), 1967-1989 (Box 38)
  - Civil Service Commission (1954-1971), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1968-1971), publications and newsletters (1971-1973), Democratic State Platform (1972), Office of Legislative Research (1973-1974), WCBS Newsradio editorial replies (1974), State of Connecticut Plan of Conservation and Development (1974), New Britain Central Labor Council (1974), Connecticut Education Association (1974), Connecticut General Assembly Joint Legislative Program Review Committee Report (1974), The Council of State Government booklet (1974), Campaign Treasurer's handbook (1974), and AFSCME International Executive Board (1975), 1954-1975 (Box 39)
  - Retirement Allowance Fund (1956), AFSCME Union booklet (1958), AFSCME; AFL-CIO promotional publications (1960s), AFL-CIO Guidebook for Union Organizers (1961), AFSCME How to Run a Union Meeting booklet (1962), General Assembly political pocket maps (1963), Municipal Employees' Retirement Fund booklet (1967), Connecticut Census (1970-1974), Connecticut Legislative Service Manuals 1-5 (1971), Connecticut Legislative Service Manuals 1-4 (1972), voting records (1973-74), Connecticut State election (1974), AFSCME International Executive Board (1974), and Office of the Secretary of State (1974), 1956-1974 (Box 40)
  - State of Connecticut Labor Department (1965-1966), Local 1716 election (1966), City of Hartford and AFSCME Agreement (1967), Connecticut Council 4 (1969), Unemployment Compensation Law (1970), AFSCME (1970-75), Badolato election (1971), Connecticut Unemployment Compensation Department (1971), Badolato's mail (1971-1972), Democratic election (1972), AFSCME President Edward Sasso (1972), AFSCME International Executive Board (1975), AFSCME related newspaper clippings (1975), AFSCME International Constitution booklet (1975), "How We Can Have Recovery Without Rekindling Inflation" booklet (1975), and AFL-CIO Convention booklets (1975), 1965-1975 (Box 41)
  - Connecticut Administrative Reports to the Governor Digest (1973-1974), Connecticut State Labor Laws manual (1974), State of Connecticut Unemployment Compensation Law manual (1974), arbitration (1975), General Assembly House of Representatives booklets (1975), unemployment compensation (1975), Connecticut Legislative Guide to Services booklet (1975), Public Work, Public Workers by Ralph J. Flynn (1975), General Assembly pocket manual (1975-1976), Committee to Re-elect Badolato (1997), and labor related newspaper clippings (2003), 1973-2003 (Box 42)
  - Connecticut Council 4 news bulletins (1976-2003) (Box 43)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1979), AFSCME International Executive Board (1982), AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education manual (1983), and AFSCME International Executive Board (1984), 1979-1984 (Box 44)
  - New Britain Charter Revision (1974), Labor Committee (1975), AFSCME International Executive Board (1979), AFSCME International Executive Board Judicial Panel (1980), AFSCME 24th International Convention Resolutions and Amendments (1980), AFSCME budget (1984), and AFSCME International Executive Board (1984), 1974-1984 (Box 45)
  - Democratic voting records (1969-1974), Badolato's mail (1970), Democratic Party (1972-1974), Connecticut State Labor Council (1972), New Britain Charter Revision Commission (1972), labor related newspaper clippings (1974), AFSCME (1974-1980), AFSCME 24th International Convention Resolutions and Amendments (1980), AFSCME 24th International Convention (1980), Legislative Committee Resolutions (1980), and AFSCME Proposed Resolutions (1982), 1969-1982 (Box 46)
  - Election (1962), Public Utilities Committee (1965), State of Connecticut Labor Department booklet (1965), Democratic State Platform (1966), election (1966), Labor Committee (1967), and General Assembly pocket manual (1967), 1962-1969 (Box 47)
  - New Britain (1950-1953), AFSCME (1963-1983), Badolato's mail (1964), City of Hartford and AFSCME Agreement (1967), Connecticut General Assembly (1967-1982), State of Connecticut Legislative Council 13th Biennial Report (1968), Badolato's mail (1968-1972), labor related newspaper clippings (1968-1972), Institute of Public Service General Assembly Report (1969), Connecticut State Labor Council AFL-CIO (1969), AFSCME Executive Board (1969), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1970), AFSCME Convention Proceedings (1970), Council #16 Convention (1971), Italian American related newspaper clippings (1974), election (1974), AFSCME PEOPLE promotional publications (1977), AFSCME (1980s-1990s), 1950-1990s (Box 48)
  - Badolato's mail and correspondence (1995-2003) (Box 49)
  - AFSCME related newspaper clippings (1969-1973), AFSCME promotional publications (1970s), AFSCME (1970s), Public Services International Activities Report (1970-1972), Connecticut State Labor Council Summer School (1971), Public Services International (1973), AFSCME International Executive Board (1973-1977), AFSCME promotional publications (1975), AFSCME budget (1976), AFSCME International Executive Board (1978), and AFSCME Legislative Briefing Conference (1981), 1969-1981 (Box 50)
  - Proposed Council-Manager Charter (1950), Charter of New Britain, Connecticut (1952), AFSCME promotional publications (1960s), Connecticut General Assembly bills (1961), House of Representatives Files (1961), Town of East Hartford Pension Plan (1963), American Goes to the Polls (1964), Collective Bargaining Agreement booklet (1967), New Britain Common Council (1967), Democratic National Committee (1968), Stafford Springs Board of Education (1969), State of Connecticut Labor Department (1970), Connecticut State Labor Council (1971), and Connecticut Master Transportation Plan manual (1973), 1950-1973 (Box 51)
  - AFSCME (1957-1997), Common Council (1964), labor related newspaper clippings (1969-2002), Connecticut Council 4 history (1972-2001), AFL-CIO newspapers (1979-1988), Connecticut Council 4 (1980s), City of New Britain and AFSCME Agreement (1986-1990), Connecticut State AFL-CIO (1986-1996), AFL-CIO Legislative Proposals (1988), Connecticut State AFL-CIO and labor related newspaper clippings (1989-1994), election (2002), Badolato's request for AFSCME membership reinstatement (2002), and AFSCME Public Employee magazines (2002-2003), 1957-2003 (Box 52)
  - Martin Luther King 20th Anniversary (1983), Jobs for Connecticut's Future Advisory Committee (1984), AFSCME (1984-90), Knaus Connecticut Council 4 building plans (1986), and vacation work planners (1988-1991), 1983-1991 (Box 53)
  - Connecticut General Assembly (1963-1969), Connecticut State Labor Council (1967-1971), AFSCME (1967-1997), Connecticut Council 4 Financial Statements (1973), Connecticut Council 4 (1976), Connecticut Council 4 newsletters (1986-1989), AFSCME 28th International Convention (1988), and Dan Rosandich cartoons (1996), 1963-1997 (Box 54)
  - Badolato's mail (1990s), United Labor Agency Board of Trustees (1997), AFSCME Financial Standards Code (1998), election (1998), Connecticut State AFL-CIO (1998), New Britain Democrats (1998), and United Labor Agency Board of Trustees (1999), 1990s-1999 (Box 55)
  - Mattabassett District (1990s) (Box 56)
  - Mattabassett District (1994-1997) (Box 57)
  - AFL-CIO (1978-2001), Creamer v. Badolato suit (1993-2000), U.S. Department of Labor (1998), Arbitrator Selection Committee (1998-2000), Connecticut State AFL-CIO (1998-2001), Public Employees Press newspapers (1998-2001), Council 15 Wage and Benefits Survey (1999), Harvard Trade Union Program (1999), National Council of Senior Citizens (1999-2000), America @ Work magazine (1999-2001), Connecticut Conference of Municipalities (2000), Italian American War Veterans (2000), AFSCME 34th International Convention Judicial Panel handbook (2000), and The Nation magazine (2001) (Box 58)
  - Mattabassett District (1998-2001) (Box 59)
  - AFSCME International Convention (1984), AFSCME (1984-1987), AFL-CIO Executive Council (1984-1987), AFSCME International Convention (1986), Connecticut Council 4 12th Convention (1987), AFL-CIO Equity in Employment Financing Act (1987), AFSCME International Convention (1988), and AFSCME International Convention (1990), 1984-1990 (Box 60)
  - AFSCME (1970s), > AFSCME International Executive Board (1973), AFSCME Local Union Training Program (1973-1974), AFSCME International Representatives manual (1974), Coalition of American Public Employees (1975), AFSCME International Executive Board (1975), AFSCME International Executive Board (1976), AFL-CIO Speakers manual (1976), and AFSCME public relations (1996), 1973-1976 (Box 61)
  - Labor (1960s-1970s), Connecticut Research Commission (1969), Fairfield University (1970s), State of Connecticut Labor Department (1970s), AFSCME (1973-1977), Connecticut Council 4 (1974), Raised Committee Bill No. 5613 (1974), Connecticut General Assembly (1976), and New Britain Herald newspaper clippings (1976) (Box 62)
  - Connecticut State AFL-CIO Convention (1983-1984), AFL-CIO Regional Conference (1984), Badolato (1984-1991), United Labor Agency (1984-1991), Connecticut State AFL-CIO (1984-1991), and Labor Committee (1985), 1983-1991 (Box 63)
  - State of Connecticut Municipal Employee Retirement System (1995), and State of Connecticut Municipal Employee Retirement Commission (1996-1997), 1995-1997 (Box 64)
  - Regulations Subcommittee (1994), Subcommittee on Hazardous Duty Service Credit (1994), actuarial valuation (1994-1995), and State of Connecticut Municipal Employee Retirement Commission (1995) (Box 65)
  - Judicial Panel Rules of Procedure booklet (1988), Connecticut Council 4 (1994-1998), AFSCME (1994-1998), Council 15 (1997), Badolato's assault police reports (1997), Connecticut Council 4 Convention (1997), AFSCME website (1997), Housing Authority of the City of Bridgeport (1997), New Haven Labor Council (1997), U.S. Department of Labor Election Guide (1997), Connecticut Council 4 Nominating Committee (1997), Committee to Re-elect Badolato (1997), Ferrucci et al v. Badolato et al (1997-2000), Ferrucci et al v. Badolato et al Judicial Panel Hearing (1998), AFSCME Financial Standards Code (1998), and Judicial Panel Report to the AFSCME International Executive Board (1998), 1988-1998 (Box 66)
  - Rhode Island Council 94 (1960s-1990s), Council 16 (1964), New York Council 37 (1981-1997), Massachusetts Council 93 (1984-1997), AFSCME Survey (1991), Council 15 (1994), Badolato's Client Lobbyist Reports (1996-1997), Communicator Lobbyist Reports (1996), Labor Board Cases (1997), Connecticut Council 4 membership (1997), State Ethics Committee (1997), Pennsylvania Council 13 (1997), and delegates meetings (1997-99), 1964-1999 (Box 67)
  - Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs (1977), AFSCME International Executive Board (1977-1978), AFSCME budget (1978, 1981), AFSCME (1981-1998), Badolato and the Gas House Gang (1990s), and The Hartford (1990s), 1977-1998 (Box 68)
  - AFSCME (1990s), AFSCME news bulletins (1993), Tim Tuttle (1993), Bob Cronin (1993), George Brockley (1993), lost time sheets (1993), Schaller Rental (1993), campaign (1993), membership figures (1993), AFSCME Corrections United Convention (1993), Charles Givens; AFSCME Local 2886 (1993), Greenwich Municipal Employees Association (1993), and AFSCME Council 15 (1993), 1992-1994 (Box 69)
  - National Daily newspapers (1984), and Connecticut Council 4 (1985-1993), 1984-1993 (Box 70)
  - Connecticut General Assembly (1950s), Public Utilities Committee (1959), Representative Badolato (1959), Democratic workshop (1960), Committee on Political Education interviews (1990), Vendor Study Committee (1995), letter from AFSCME Local 2663 (1995), Sonia Camargo (1995), Kerry E. Dave (1995), Zabit and Associates (1995), and Connecticut Institute of Municipal Studies (1996), 1950s-1996 (Box 71)
  - International labor (1950s-1960s), arbitration (1950s-1960s), Labor Problems (1959), Public Service International (1962), Labor Relations Committee (1962-1963), health and welfare (1963), wage administration (1963), Trade Union Program (1963), Speaker's handbook (1964), Modern Dues for a Modern Union booklet (1964), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1968), AFSCME Local Union Training (1969), University of Connecticut Labor Education Center (1976), and AFSCME (1970s-1980s), 1950s-1980s (Box 72)
  - Election (1956), election (1958), election (1960), Connecticut General Assembly bills (1961), Connecticut Council 4 budget analysis (1965-1966), AFSCME (1970s-1980s), Connecticut Council 4 (1973), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1973), campaign issues (1976), State Labor Department (1978), and Walter F. Mondale (1983), 1950s-1980s (Box 73)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1985-1986), Hudson Decision (1986-1987), Connecticut State AFL-CIO financial statements (1992-1993), Public Acts (1993), Corrections Congress (1993), health care reform (1994), Frederick T. Garrity (1994), Ann Cummings (1994), John Flavin (1994), Judith Johnston (1994), AFL-CIO (1994), Connecticut Council 4 (1996), Judi C. Rossi (1996), Frank C. Greco (1997), Kelley Beaucar (1997), Charles Zimbouski (1997), James Cenerini (1997), David J. Glidden (1997), and AFSCME Local 1303-293 (1997), 1985-1997 (Box 74)
  - Labor related newspapers (1971-1973) (Box 75)
  - Labor related handbooks and publications (1940s-1960s), Connecticut State Legislature (1960s), Badolato mail (1960s), University of Connecticut Labor Education Center (1960s), Hartford, Connecticut Salary Administration Plans (1960), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1961), General City Ordinances (1961), and Connecticut General Assembly (1963) (Box 76)
  - Judicial Panel Study Committee (1979), AFSCME International Executive Board (1980), AFSCME International Executive Board (1980), AFSCME requests for waivers (1981), and Bridgeport Financial Review Board (1989), 1979-1981 (Box 77)
  - AFSCME 11th Biennial Convention (1985), AFSCME (1988-1989), Bridgeport Financial Review Board (1989), and AFSCME (1994-1995), 1985-1995 (Box 78)
  - Labor related handbooks and publications (1940s-1960s), Badolato's mail (1950s), New Britain, Connecticut Directory (1959), Hartford, Connecticut Directory (1959), Connecticut House of Representatives (1961), and New Britain, Connecticut Directory (1962), 1940s-1962 (Box 79)
  - Connecticut Register and Manual (1963), State Scholarship Commission Report (1963-1964), America Goes to the Polls (1964), State of Connecticut House of ' Representatives (1965), State of Connecticut General Assembly Legislative Record Index (1965), Badolato mail (1965-1972), AFSCME (1972), and State of Connecticut General Assembly (1975), 1963-1975 (Box 80)
  - Connecticut Council 4 (1986), AFSCME 50th Anniversary Celebration (1988), and AFSCME Commercial Drivers License Study Programs (1990), 1986-1990 (Box 81)
  - AFSCME (1987-1995) (Box 82)
  - AFSCME (1989), Public Services International (1993), State of Connecticut Medical and Dental Plan (1993), Special Olympics World Games (1995), and AFL-CIO Convention (1995), 1989-1995 (Box 83)
  - AFSCME (1975), Connecticut Council 4 (1991), Connecticut State AFL-CIO (1993-1994), George Meany Center for Labor Studies (1994-1995), A New Voice for American Workers delegate kit (1995), AFSCME (1995), Labor Institute of Public Affairs (1995), Prospering in America (1995), Connecticut AFL-CIO (1996), AFSCME 32nd International Convention (1996), AFSCME (1996), Connecticut Council 4 (1996), and Special Constitutional Convention of AFL-CIO (1996), 1975-1996 (Box 84)
  - Badolato portfolio (1960s) and AFSCME (1972-1973), 1961-1973 (Box 85)
  - AFSCME Constitution (1964-1966), AFSCME 16th International Convention (1966), AFSCME Constitution (1970), New York State Grievance Procedures Report (1970) AFSCME (1971-1972), AFSCME 19th International Convention (1972), 1964-1972 (Box 86)
  - AFSCME (1960s-1970s) and labor related newspapers (1968-1971) (Box 87)
  - State of Connecticut Trial Court (1973-1974), State of Connecticut General Assembly (1974-1976), James K. Robertson, Jr. (1974), U.S. Department of Labor (1974), Council of State Governments (1975), legislative handbooks (1975), and Badolato mail (1975-1976), 1973-1976 (Box 88)
  - AFSCME (1970s-1980s) (Box 89)
  - Connecticut Register and Manual (1963), Constitution of the State of Connecticut (1966), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1968-1971), The Job Safety and Health Act (1970), National Academy of Arbitrators 22nd Annual Meeting (1970), AFSCME 18th International Convention (1970), AFL-CIO 9th Constitutional Convention (1971), Personal Administration and the Law (1972), AFSCME Political Education Program (1973-1974), Connecticut State Election (1977), Connecticut State AFL-CIO Convention (1982), and AFSCME Convention Resolutions (1984), 1963-1984 (Box 90)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1970) and AFSCME International Executive Board (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 91)
  - Connecticut General Assembly (1961), General Election Statement of Vote (1962, 1966), Connecticut General Assembly (1963, 1967), Connecticut General Election (1970s), Connecticut House of Representatives (1971), municipal collective bargaining (1971), and Badolato mail (1971), 1961-1971 (Box 92)
  - AFSCME Executive Board (1986-87), 1986-1987 (Box 93)
  - AFSCME Executive Board (1991) (Box 94)
  - AFSCME Executive Board (1987-92), 1987-1992 (Box 95)
  - Labor related newspapers (1967-1970), Connecticut Labor Department (1969-1971), AFL-CIO news bulletins (1970), Area Wage Survey (1970), State Workmen's Compensation Law (1970), major collective bargaining agreements (1970), U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (1970), Connecticut Market Data Report (1970), legislative bulletins (1971), AFSCME International Executive Board (1972), Summery of Public Acts (1973-1974), and Connecticut State General Election (1975), 1967-1976 (Box 96)
  - Labor related handbooks (1960s-1970s), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1970s), Badolato mail (1970s), State of Connecticut Senate (1971), State of Connecticut House of Representatives (1971), Connecticut General Assembly (1971-1976), and American Arbitration Association (1975) (Box 97)
  - AFSCME (1989-1992) (Box 98)
  - AFSCME (1983-1989) (Box 99)